<resources>

    <string name="app_name">RPCNA Constitution</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string-array name="RPC_menu_items">
        <item>West. Confession &amp; RP Testimony</item>
        <item>Larger Catechism</item>
        <item>Shorter Catechism</item>
        <item>Directory for Church Government</item>
        <item>Book of Discipline</item>
        <item>Directory of Public Worship</item>
        <item>Vows</item>
        <item>Suggested Forms</item>
        <item>History of the Standards</item>
        <item>Covenant of 1871</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="RPC_documents">
        <item>Westy!!! Westy!!!</item>
        <item>Larger Catechism</item>
        <item>Shorter Catechism</item>
        <item>Directory for Church Government</item>
        <item>Book of Discipline</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>The Directory of Public Worship</h2><h4>Adopted 2010</h4><p><b>Preamble</b></p><p>The purpose of this directory is to guide the worship of the church according to the Scriptures as summarized in the standards of the Reformed Presbyterian Church of North America.</p><p><b>Chapter 1 - The Nature of Worship</b></p><p>1. God made man in His image to glorify and enjoy Him. In the public worship of the church, the people of God, redeemed by Christ, glorify and enjoy the triune God, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, as He reveals Himself in His Word.</p><p>2. The main purpose of worship is to bring glory to the triune God, particularly for His work of redemption through Jesus Christ. However, God, in His benevolence, also invites and commands His people to draw near to Him to experience all the benefits of their redemption, to declare their dependence on Him, to enjoy His appointed means of grace, to encourage one another, to celebrate their union with Jesus Christ and to be transformed, more and more, into His image.</p><p>3. In the corporate worship of the church the triune God meets with His people in accordance with the terms of the Covenant of Grace. In worship the church remembers God\'s covenant of grace and renews her commitment to her Lord. Worship involves intimate communion between God and His redeemed people. In worship God initiates a covenantal dialogue with His people in which He calls them to worship, declares to them His great acts of creation and redemption, assures them of the efficacy of His promises, and seals His promises to them by means of sacraments. In response to God\'s initiative, the people of God offer prayers of confession, petition, and thanksgiving, sing Psalms with grace in their hearts, receive God\'s word as it is both read and preached, make offerings to Him and seal their personal and corporate commitment to Him through the sacraments.</p><p>4. Because worship involves drawing near to the living and holy God, God\'s people should enter public worship prepared for communion with Him. In addition, pastors and elders should lead the congregation in public worship in a manner commensurate with the joy, dignity, solemnity and glory of such a holy occasion. All of God\'s people should enter His presence with both reverence and awe.</p><p>5. Jesus Christ is the sole mediator of the Covenant of Grace and the only mediator between God and man. Therefore, the worship of God\'s people is acceptable to God only as it is offered in Christ\'s name and through humble reliance on His High Priestly intercession and service.</p><p>6. Jesus Christ, as our Prophet, Priest and King, has revealed to His people how to worship Him in a pleasing manner. Therefore, \"the acceptable way of worshiping the true God is instituted by Himself and so limited by His own revealed will, that He may not be worshiped according to the imaginations and devices of men, or the suggestions of Satan, under any visible representation, or any other way not prescribed in the Holy Scriptures\" (WCF 21:1).</p><p>7. In His Word, God has specially appointed one day in seven, the Sabbath day, for His people to assemble for the purpose of public corporate worship. Since the resurrection of our Lord, the first day of the week, the Lord\'s Day, has been set aside as the Christian Sabbath, to be kept holy as the day for the church\'s worship and for rest from regular work.</p><p>8. Given the high calling and privilege of public worship, the people of God should prepare their hearts and come to worship with a joyous willingness, not absenting themselves through indifference or because of family activities or other Christian meetings. In normal circumstances, neither personal devotions nor family worship are to be regarded as proper substitutes for public worship. In addition to attending the scheduled services of public worship, the Lord\'s Day may be fruitfully observed through activities such as: personal Bible reading and study, meditation and prayer, discussion of the sermon, the enjoyment of physical rest, acts of mercy, spiritual fellowship, hospitality, instructing and catechizing the children and visiting the sick.</p><p><b>Chapter 2 - The Practice of Worship</b></p><p>1. The Scriptures do not prescribe a fixed order of worship, but so that all things may be done decently and in order (I Cor. 14:40), it is desirable that the exercises of worship be conducted in a biblical, thoughtful, dignified, and edifying manner. The assembled congregation meets in God\'s presence as His covenant people: They confess their sins, hear His promises of forgiveness and acceptance, and listen to the righteous requirements of His Word. The whole is a dialogue between God and His people. The order and content of the service should reflect this dialogue that occurs on the basis of the Covenant of Grace. The following order of service is suggested, although it may be varied:</p><p>Call to Worship, and Greeting<br/>Prayer of Adoration<br/>Psalm<br/><i>Baptism, when administered</i><br/>Old Testament Reading<br/>Psalm, or Prayer of Confession<br/>New Testament Reading<br/>Prayer of Intercession<br/>Scripture Text for Sermon<br/>Sermon<br/>Prayer<br/>Presentation of Tithes and Offerings<br/><i>Lord\'s Supper, when administered:<br/>Words of Institution<br/>Warning and Invitation<br/>Celebration of the Lord\'s Supper</i><br/>Psalm<br/>Benediction</p><p>2. The scriptural elements of ordinary public worship are prayer, the singing of Psalms, the reading, preaching, and hearing of the Word of God, the presentation of tithes and offerings, and the celebration of the sacraments. To these may be added the special ordinances of fasting, thanksgiving, taking of oaths and vows, and public covenanting. Each part of the service should be briefly explained at regular intervals in contemporary terms, so as to make its purpose clear to all present. Announcements should be made prior to or after the service and kept to a minimum so as not to intrude upon the worship of God.</p><p>3. The local session is responsible for the immediate oversight of public worship. Ordinarily the pastor takes the leadership role in planning and conducting the worship service. Ruling elders may call the congregation to worship and give the greeting, lead the congregation in prayer, introduce the Psalms to be sung, and read the Scripture. On occasion a ruling elder may preach the Word and pronounce the benediction, but he may not administer the sacraments except under extraordinary circumstances (DCG 3:I:C:4-6). On occasion a student under care may lead part of the service.</p>]]></item>
        <item>Vows</item>
        <item>Suggested Forms</item>
        <item>History of the Standards</item>
        <item>Covenant of 1871</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
