<resources>

    <string name="app_name">RPCNA Constitution</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string-array name="navdrawer_items">
        <item>West. Confession &amp; RP Testimony</item>
        <item>Larger Catechism</item>
        <item>Shorter Catechism</item>
        <item>Directory for Church Government</item>
        <item>Book of Discipline</item>
        <item>Directory of Public Worship</item>
        <item>Vows</item>
        <item>Suggested Forms</item>
        <item>History</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="history_menu_items">
        <item>History: Introduction</item>
        <item>History: Covenant of 1871</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="history_text">
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>History</h2><p>The Reformed Presbyterian Church of North America is a branch of the Church Visible and is presbyterian in its form of government. It holds the doctrines and principles of the Protestant Reformation of the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, and, in particular, testifies to the duty of public covenanting by churches and nations. It accepts the Scriptures of the Old and New Testaments as the Word of God, the supreme and infallible rule of faith and life, and its subordinate standards as \"agreeable unto and founded upon\" them. These subordinate standards are: The Westminster Confession of Faith; the Catechisms, Larger and Shorter; the Testimony of the Reformed Presbyterian Church of North America; the Directory for Church Government; the Book of Discipline and the Directory for Worship.</p><p>The first known organized congregation of the Reformed Presbyterian Church in American was that of Middle Octorara, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania (1738). The Reformed Presbytery was constituted in 1774 by ministers sent for that purpose: John Cuthbertson, who came from Scotland in 1752, and Matthew Linn and Alexander Dobbin, who came from Ireland in 1774. After its dissolution in 1782 the Reformed Presbytery of the United States of North American was constituted in 1798, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. The Synod was constituted in 1809.</p><p>The first record now extant of Church Standards is a reference in 1802 to an earlier decision \"to display a judicial testimony for truth and against error.\" In 1804 Presbytery ordered the preparation of a three-fold Testimony, Historical, Declaratory, and Argumentative. In 1806 Presbytery adopted the Historical View, with a Preface, and the Declaration and Testimony.</p><p>In 1834 a continuation of the Historical View through 1833 was approved. This document was never included with the standards named in the Terms of Communion. A complete revision of it, continuing the history to the present time and written especially for young people, was authorized in 1921, and published in booklet form in 1929, entitled \"A Brief History of the Reformed Presbyterian Church.\"</p><p>The Argumentative Testimony was designed to examine the various systems of doctrine considered hostile to the Reformation and to warn against them individually. At least four chapters were prepared in overture by 1841. In 1845 the plan of work was changed. No final action was ever taken.</p><p>The Declaration and Testimony was amended in 1823 by the addition of a chapter on Adoption, with its proof texts added in 1834. In 1861 a section was added on Secret Associations (chap. 22.5 and error 7) and one on Slavery (29.4 and errors 7 and 10). In 1883 a section on Temperance was added (xxii. 6 and error 9). These sections confirmed officially in permanent form positions long held by the church. (Secrecy--from the beginning, as was stated by Synod in 1821. Slavery--errors 8 and 9 were in the original Testimony. Temperance--a cumulative witness, recorded from 1801 on). In 1928 chapters 29 and 30 were revised.</p><p>In 1807 Presbytery adopted revisions of the Terms of Communion and the Formula of Queries. The original Terms and Queries, of which there is no record extant, evidently were those of the Presbyteries in Scotland and Ireland (for these, see Hutchison\'s <i>The Reformed Presbyterian Church</i>, p. 213). In the Terms and Queries now adopted is found the only extant record of the place occupied as subordinate standards by the Westminster documents--Confession of Faith, Larger and Shorter Catechisms, Form of Church Government, and Directory for Worship--and by the National Covenant of Scotland and the Solemn League and Covenant. The Westminster standards were approved \"as they were received by the Church of Scotland.\" The reference is to the Acts of this Church approving the documents (see regular editions of these standards). The Church made two reservations regarding the Confession of Faith, as to the lack of mention of the different ecclesiastical officers, and as to chapter 31.2 on the relation of magistrates to the Church. Reservations were made in adopting the Directory for Worship, as to the observance of the Lord\'s Supper, and as to particular items of order and practice appointed by the Church. Reservations were made in adopting the Form of Government as to the doctor or teacher, and as to relations of presbyteries and people in the calling of ministers. These points are covered by declarations in the American standards. Throughout this present volume, the earlier documents are to be interpreted by those adopted later.</p><p>The Terms were amended in 1823 by the substitution of the name of the Synod. In 1841 the second statement of the First Term was restored, after years of omission in printed copies. In 1878 the Fourth Term was amended to include the Covenant of 1871. In 1938 a complete revision was adopted, and in 1948 the new Fourth Term was amended to fit the revised standards. In connection with the revision of 1938 a Covenant of Church Membership was adopted. The Queries were revised in 1939, to conform to the revised Terms.</p><p>In 1802 Presbytery appointed a minister to prepare a Form of Covenant, \"containing the spirit of the National and Solemn League.\" Various forms were prepared in later years, but none was adopted until the one solemnly subscribed by Synod in 1871, and by the several congregations. Fifty years after, in 1921, Synod adopted an \"Additional Statement,\" but did not submit it in overture.</p><p>In 1807 Presbytery took steps to prepare a Directory for the Worship of God and a Book of Discipline. Both were adopted in 1819, and Forms of Process were ordered prepared to accompany the latter. The Directory was not published, and the Westminster Directory remained the standard until 1945. The Book of Discipline was not published. A revised draft was published in 1836, with the Forms. It was amended and adopted in 1841, and the Forms were approved. Extensive amendments were adopted in 1863.</p><p>In 1819 and in 1836 a Form of Church Government was submitted in overture. Neither Form was adopted, and the Westminster Form remained the standard. In 1863 Rules of Procedure for conducting ecclesiastical business, taken almost entirely from chapter iii. of the proposed Book of 1836, were adopted, and served as a supplement to the Westminster form. \"Rules for directing the organization and proceedings of\" (Presbytery and) Synod were listed in 1802 and revised last in 1874.</p><p>It appears that the Westminster standards, with the exception of the Form of Government, were not printed by the Church in her official publications. In 1806 the Declaration and Testimony and the Historical View were published in one volume, entitled \"Reformation Principles.\" In 1834 the Terms of Communion and the Queries were included in this volume. In 1874 the Covenant of 1871 was included. A second volume was published in 1841, containing the Westminster Form of Government, the Book of Discipline with the Forms, the Terms of Communion and the Queries. There were added in 1863 the Rules of Procedure; in 1874 the Rules for the meetings of Synod; and also the Covenant of 1871.</p><p>A committee of four men was appointed in 1939 to the work of revision. The revised Form of Government (including the Rules of Procedure and Rules for Meetings of Synod), Book of Discipline and Directory for Worship were sent down in overture, and in 1945 were declared adopted by the Church.</p><p>The Synod of 1969 gave approval to the \"rewriting of the Testimony of the Church without change in the system of theology.\" A committee chaired by James D. Carson completed the task by 1979 when the full document went down in overture. The 1980 Synod declared the revised Testimony to be the law and order of the Church. It is presented in a form which enhances the teaching of the Confession, yet speaks to issues of the day without unnecessary duplication.</p><p>Following several years of study by the Synod on \"Officers of the Church\" the Synod of 1981 appointed a special committee chaired by Bruce C. Stewart to revise and rewrite the Form of Church Government, taking into consideration the conclusions regarding the nature of the eldership already adopted by Synod. The procedure of the committee was to add principial parts of the previous Form of Church Government to appropriate chapters in the Testimony, and to put procedural parts in a new Directory for Church Government. All of the proposed changes were adopted by the Synod of 1986 and sent down in overture. The 1987 Synod declared the revisions to the Testimony and the new Directory for Church Government to be the law and order of the church. The revision of the Forms in the back of the Directory for Church Government was approved by the 1987 Synod.</p>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>Covenant of 1871</h2><p>Believing assuredly that in covenanting with God, and thereby binding our souls by oath to fear and serve Him, we do make a near approach into His august and holy presence, and knowing that they only are approved and accepted who come with self-abasement, filled with shame and godly sorrow, and ingenuously confessing and forsaking their sins, according to that word, \"If we confess our sins, He is faithful and just to forgive us our sins, and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness\" [1 John 1:9], we do now give glory to the Lord God of Israel, and make confession unto Him.</p><p>We do humbly and sincerely confess and lament that we have not duly valued and improved the unsearchable riches of truth and grace in the Holy Scriptures, by making them our constant, earnest and prayerful study, by accepting Christ in all His fulness of saving blessings, and by seeking for the Holy Spirit in His illuminating and renewing grace to apply to our souls the redemption of Christ, and thus reconcile us unto God, and make us partakers of everlasting life.</p><p>We acknowledge, with shame, want of faith in God and in the promises and threatenings of His Word, formality in religious services, pride, selfishness, vanity, conformity to the spirit of the world, lukewarmness, untenderness in our walk and in our dealings with others, unwatchfulness, sinful security, and want of spirituality in our disposition and deportment. We are chargeable with remissness in the duties of the closet, the family, the prayer-meeting, and the sanctuary. We have not hallowed the Sabbath by observing it with the care and sacredness required by the divine Commandment. We have shown criminal apathy and unfaithfulness in that we have not cherished love for all men, and especially for the faithful in Christ Jesus, and in that we have not exhorted one another daily, and sought to promote the spiritual growth and holiness of the saints.</p><p>We mourn that religion has not been cultivated and practiced in our homes as it should have been. Parents have not felt in any adequate measure their responsibility for the salvation of their children; and in consequence, family worship, reading the Scriptures in the household, instruction in the accepted manuals of the faith of the Church, and pleading the covenant and promise of God on behalf of our seed, are mournfully neglected.</p><p>We lament that, as professing witnesses for Christ, we have failed in obedience to His command to preach the Gospel to every creature, to make known His will and law among the nations, and to administer with fidelity the law and discipline of His own house. While property is hoarded up, or wasted upon the luxuries and vanities of life, and in very many cases upon objects pernicious to both body and soul, means are wanting to make known the way of salvation in the sight of the heathen. We confess and bewail our forgetfulness of the obligations laid upon us by the Covenants of our fathers, in that we have often walked contrary thereunto, in not testifying fully and clearly in word and act for the claims of Jesus Christ, the Head of the Church, and the Prince of the kings of the earth. We have sinned, too, in that, while witnessing for social covenanting as an ordinance of God, binding under the dispensation of the Gospel, we have not as a Church in this country, by our own act, performed the duty.</p><p>We humble ourselves in the sight of the Just and Holy One, in view of the many and great iniquities of the land in which we live. The nation refuses to own its responsibility to God and to the Mediator, to recognize the supremacy of the Bible in national affairs, and to countenance and encourage the true Christian religion. Atheists, infidels, and all classes of vile men, are made constitutionally eligible to the most responsible positions under the government. Consonant with these essential effects, the history of the government has been largely one of oppression and injustice towards its aboriginal and colored people, and of iniquitous distinction of caste; while Sabbath desecration, prostitution of the oath, official corruption and dishonesty, profanation of the name of God, murder, drunkenness, excess and rioting, violation of the ordinance of marriage, vanity of apparel, sinful extravagance, lying and deceit, are become common and ordinary sins. These, and all other transgressions whereof our people and land are guilty, we desire to acknowledge, and to be humbled on account of them, that all men may see that righteousness belongeth unto God, and shame and confusion of face unto us, as appears this day.</p><p>And because the promise of mercy is made to those who not only confess, but forsake their sin, we do resolve and engage before the Lord carefully to avoid, for the time to come, all these offences, together with temptations leading thereunto; and to testify the integrity of our hearts in this resolution and engagement, and that we may be the better enabled in the power of the Lord\'s strength to perform the same, we, in obedience to the command of God, comformably to the practice of the godly in former times and recognizing all that is moral in the Covenants of our worthy religious progenitors of the Second Reformation, do hereby give ourselves in covenant to God, to His Church, and to one another.</p><h4>Covenant</h4><p>We, Ministers, Elders, Deacons, and Members of the REFORMED PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH IN NORTH AMERICA, with our hands lifted up, do jointly and severally swear by the Great and Dreadful Name of the Lord our God:</p><p>1. That coming into the presence of the Lord God with a deep conviction of His awful majesty and glory, of His omniscience, His purity, His justice and His grace; of our guilt and total depravity by nature, and our utter inability to save ourselves from deserved condemnation to everlasting punishment; with renunciation of all dependence on our own righteousness as the ground of pardon and acceptance with God, we receive for ourselves and for our children the Lord Jesus Christ as He is offered in the Gospel to be our Saviour--The Holy Spirit to be our Enlightener, Sanctifier and Guide--and God, the Father, to be our everlasting portion; we approve and accept of the Covenant of Grace as all our salvation and desire, and take the moral law as dispensed by the Mediator, Christ, to be the rule of our life, and to be obeyed by us in all its precepts and prohibitions.</p><p>Aiming to live for the glory of God as our chief end, we will, in reliance upon God\'s grace, and feeling our inability to perform any spiritual duty in our own strength, diligently attend to searching the Scriptures, religious conversation, the duties of the closet, the household, the fellowship-meeting and the sanctuary, and will seek in them to worship God in spirit and in truth. We do solemnly promise to depart from all iniquity, and to live soberly, righteously, and godly in this present world, commending and encouraging, by our example, temperance, charity and godliness.</p><p>2. That after careful examination, having embraced the system of faith, order and worship revealed in the Holy Scriptures, and summarized, as to doctrine, in the <i>Westminster Confession</i> and <i>Catechisms</i>, and <i>Reformed Presbyterian Testimony</i>, and, as to order and worship, justly set forth in substance and outline in the <i>Westminster Form of Church Government</i> and <i>Directory for Worship</i>, we do publicly profess and own this as the true Christian faith and religion, and the system of order and worship appointed by Christ for His own house, and, by the grace of God, we will sincerely and constantly endeavor to understand it more fully, to hold and observe it in its integrity, and to transmit the knowledge of the same to posterity. We solemnly reject whatever is known by us to be contrary to the Word of God, our recognized and approved manuals of faith and order, and the great principles of the Protestant Reformation. Particularly, we abjure and condemn Infidelity, under all its various aspects; Atheism, or the denial of the divine existence; Pantheism with its denial of the divine personality; Naturalism, with its denial of the divine Providential Government; Spiritualism, with its denial of the Bible redemption; Indifferentism, with its denial of man\'s responsibility; Formalism, with its denial of the power of godliness. We abjure and condemn Popery, with its arrogant assumption of supremacy and infallibility; its corrupt and heretical teachings; its dogma of the Immaculate Conception; its hostility to civil and religious liberty, to the progress of society in civilization and intelligence, and especially its denial, in common with Infidelity, of the right and duty of the State to educate in morality and religion by the use of the Bible in schools enjoying its patronage and support.</p><p>Believing Presbyterianism to be the only divinely instituted form of government in the Christian Church, we disown and reject all others forms of ecclesiastical polity, as without authority of Scripture, and as damaging to purity, peace and unity in the household of faith.</p><p>We reject all systems of false religion and will-worship, and with these all forms of secret oath-bound societies and orders, as ensnaring in their nature, pernicious in their tendency, and perilous to the liberties of both Church and State; and pledge ourselves to pray and labor according to our power, that whatever is contrary to godliness may be removed, and the Church beautified with universal conformity to the law and will of her Divine Head and Lord.</p><p>3. Persuaded that God is the source of all legitimate power; that He has instituted civil government for His own glory and the good of man; that He has appointed His Son, the Mediator, to headship over the nations; and that the Bible is the supreme law and rule in national as in all other things, we will maintain the responsibility of nations to God, the rightful dominion of Jesus Christ over the commonwealth, and the obligation of nations to legislate in conformity with the written Word. We take ourselves sacredly bound to regulate all our civil relations, attachments, professions and deportment, by our allegiance and loyalty to the Lord, our King, Lawgiver and Judge; and by this, our oath, we are pledged to promote the interests of public order and justice, to support cheerfully whatever is for the good of the commonwealth in which we dwell, and to pursue this object in all things not forbidden by the law of God, or inconsistent with public dissent from an unscriptural and immoral civil power.</p><p>We will pray and labor for the peace and welfare of our country, and for its reformation by a constitutional recognition of God as the source of all power, of Jesus Christ as the Ruler of Nations, of the Holy Scriptures as the supreme rule, and of the true Christian religion; and we will continue to refuse to incorporate by any act, with the political body, until this blessed reformation has been secured.</p><p>4. That, believing the Church to be <i>one</i>, and that all the saints have communion with God and with one another in the same Covenant; believing, moreover, that schism and sectarianism are sinful in themselves; and inimical to true religion, and trusting that divisions shall cease, and the people of God become one Catholic church over all the earth, we will pray and labor for the visible oneness of the Church of God in our own land and throughout the world, on the basis of truth and of Scriptural order. Considering it a principal duty of our profession to cultivate a holy brotherhood, we will strive to maintain Christian friendship with pious men of every name, and to feel and act as one with all in every land who pursue this grand end. And, as a means of securing this great result, we will by dissemination and application of the principles of truth herein professed, and by cultivating and exercising Christian charity, labor to remove stumbling-blocks, and to gather into one the scattered and divided friends of truth and righteousness.</p><p>5. Rejoicing that the enthroned Mediator is not only King in Zion, but King over all the earth, and recognizing the obligation of His command to go into all the world and preach the gospel to every creature, and to teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father, of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost, and resting with faith in the promise of His perpetual presence as the pledge of success, we hereby dedicate ourselves to the great work of making known God\'s light and salvation among the nations, and to this end will labor that the Church may be provided with an earnest, self-denying and able ministry. Profoundly conscious of past remissness and neglect, we will henceforth, by our prayers, pecuniary contributions and personal exertions, seek the revival of pure and undefiled religion, the conversion of Jews and Gentiles to Christ, that all men may be blessed in Him, and that all nations may call Him blessed.</p><p>6. Committing ourselves with all our interests to the keeping of Him in whom we have believed; in faithfulness to our own vows, and to the Covenants of our fathers, and to our children whom we desire to lead in the right ways of the Lord; in love to all mankind, especially the household of faith; in obedience to the commandment of the everlasting God to contend earnestly for the faith once delivered to the saints, we will bear true testimony in word and in deed for every known part of divine truth, and for all the ordinances appointed by Christ in His kingdom; and we will tenderly and charitably, but plainly and decidedly, oppose and discountenance all and every known error, immorality, neglect or perversion of divine institutions. Taking as our example the faithful in all ages, and, most of all, the blessed Master Himself, and withour eye fixed upon the great cloud of witnesses who have sealed with their blood the testimony which they held, we will strive to hold fast the profession of our faith without wavering, in hope of the crown of life which fadeth not away.</p><p>Finally, we enter upon this solemn act of covenanting before the Omniscient God, with unfeigned purpose of paying our vow. All sinister and selfish ends and motives we solemnly disavow, and protest that we have no aim but the glory of God, and the present and everlasting welfare of immortal souls. And our prayer to God is and shall be to strengthen us by His Holy Spirit to keep this our promise, vow and oath, and to bless our humble attempt to glorify His name and honor His truth and cause with such success as will bring salvation to our own souls, the wider spread and triumph of truth and holiness, and the enlargement and establishment of the kingdom of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, to whom, with the Father and the Spirit, one God, be glory in the Church throughout all ages, world without end. AMEN.</p>]]></item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="vows_menu_items">
        <item>Vows: Communicant Membership</item>
        <item>Vows: Ordination</item>
        <item>Vows: Baptism</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="vows_text">
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>Covenant of Communicant Membership</h2><p>1. Do you believe the Scriptures of the Old and New Testaments to be the Word of God, the only infallible rule for faith and life?</p><p>2. Do you believe in the one living and true God--Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, as revealed in the Scriptures?</p><p>3. Do you repent of your sin; confess your guilt and helplessness as a sinner against God; profess Jesus Christ, Son of God, as your Saviour and Lord; and dedicate yourself to His service: Do you promise that you will endeavor to forsake all sin, and to conform your life to His teaching and example?</p><p>4. Do you promise to submit in the Lord to the teaching and government of this church as being based upon the Scriptures and described in substance in the <i>Constitution of the Reformed Presbyterian Church of North America</i>? Do you recognize your responsibility to work with others in the church and do you promise to support and encourage them in their service to the Lord? In case you should need correction in doctrine or life, do you promise to respect the authority and discipline of the church?</p><p>5. To the end that you may grow in the Christian life, do you promise that you will diligently read the Bible, engage in private prayer, keep the Lord\'s Day, regularly attend the worship services, observe the appointed sacraments, and give to the Lord\'s work as He shall prosper you?</p><p>6. Do you purpose to seek first the kingdom of God and His righteousness in all the relationships of life, faithfully to perform your whole duty as a true servant of Jesus Christ, and seek to win others to Him?</p><p>7. Do you make this profession of faith and purpose in the presence of God, in humble reliance upon His grace, as you desire to give your account with joy at the Last Great Day?</p>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>Queries for Ordination, Installation, and Licensure</h2><p>1. Do you believe the Scriptures of the Old and New Testaments to be the Word of God, and the only infallible rule of faith and life?</p><p>2. Do you believe that the Lord Jesus Christ is the Son of God and the only Redeemer of men, and do you confess Him publicly as your Saviour and Lord?</p><p>3. Do you believe that it is the duty of Christians to profess publicly the content of faith as it applies to the particular needs of each age and situation, and that such public profession, otherwise called covenanting, should be made formally by the churches and other institutions as well as informally by each believer according to his ability?</p><p>4. Do you believe in and accept the system of doctrine and the manner of worship set forth in the <i>Westminster Confession of Faith</i>, the <i>Larger</i> and <i>Shorter</i> Catechisms, and the <i>Testimony of the Reformed Presbyterian Church</i>, as being agreeable to, and founded upon, the Scriptures?</p><p>5. Do you believe it to be the teaching of Scripture--that church and state are distinct and separate institutions; that both are under the mediatorial rule of the Lord Jesus Christ; and that the permanent form of church government is presbyterian?</p><p>6. Do you believe that Jesus Christ is Saviour and Lord of men and nations, and that in loyalty and obedience to Him, it is our duty to follow the noble example of the faithful confessors and martyrs of Jesus in their witness for divine truth, and in their sacrifices and labors to establish the Kingdom of God on earth?</p><p>7. So far as you can know in your own heart, is it the call of Christ, the glory of God and the welfare of the church, and not any selfish object, that moves you to undertake this sacred office?</p><p>8. That you may perform faithfully all the duties of the office to which you have been called, do you engage to seek the guidance of the Holy Spirit? Do you promise, in His strength, to live a holy and exemplary life, to study and promote the purity, peace, unity and progress of the church--</p><p>(<i>to deacons</i>): to lead the congregation in the ministry of mercy, to practice the grace of scriptural stewardship, to cultiviate it in the congregation, and to endeavor to handle the Lord\'s money in a manner which is efficient and above reproach?</p><p>(<i>to elders</i>): to watch over the spiritual growth of the members of the congregation, to endeavor to win others to Christ, to visit the afflicted and to attend the meetings associated with your office?</p><p>(<i>to persons certified to preach, or to licentiates</i>): to seek diligently to become an able expositor of the Word, an understanding and helpful counselor, a true minister of God?</p><p>(<i>to ministers</i>): to bring to your congregation the fruits of earnest study of the Word, to maintain a testimony for the Kingdom of God, to endeavor to minister to others and win them to Christ, to watch for souls as one who must give account?</p><p>9. Do you promise subjection in the Lord to the courts of this church, and engage to follow no divisive courses from the doctrine and order which the church has solemnly recognized and adopted; and do you promise to submit to all the brotherly counsel which your brethren may tender you in the Lord?</p>]]></item>
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>Covenant of Baptism</h2>1. Do you believe this child is a possession of God entrusted to your care?</p><p>2. In this light, do you promise to provide for his/her temporal well-being, to teach him/her to love God and His Word, the Bible, and to provide him/her with a God-centered education?</p><p>3. Do you promise to teach him/her of his/her sinful nature, of the plan of salvation which centers in Jesus Christ, and his/her own personal need of a relationship with Christ?</p><p>4. To the end that he/she may grow in the Christian life, do you promise to pray for him/her, and to train him/her to read the Bible, to pray, to keep the Lord\'s Day and to understand the nature of the Church, the value of its worship and fellowship, and his/her need to seek communicant membership in the church?</p><p>5. Do you promise to lead him/her, by your example and parental discipline exercised in love, to seek first the Kingdom of God and His righteousness in all the relationships of life?</p><p>6. Do you make these promises in the presence of God, in humble reliance upon His grace, as you desire to give your account with joy at the Last Great Day?</p>]]></item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string-array name="RPC_documents">
        <item>Westy!!! Westy!!!</item>
        <item>Larger Catechism</item>
        <item>Shorter Catechism</item>
        <item>Directory for Church Government</item>
        <item>Book of Discipline</item>
        <item><![CDATA[<h2>The Directory of Public Worship</h2><h4>Adopted 2010</h4><p><b>Preamble</b></p><p>The purpose of this directory is to guide the worship of the church according to the Scriptures as summarized in the standards of the Reformed Presbyterian Church of North America.</p><p><b>Chapter 1 - The Nature of Worship</b></p><p>1. God made man in His image to glorify and enjoy Him. In the public worship of the church, the people of God, redeemed by Christ, glorify and enjoy the triune God, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, as He reveals Himself in His Word.</p><p>2. The main purpose of worship is to bring glory to the triune God, particularly for His work of redemption through Jesus Christ. However, God, in His benevolence, also invites and commands His people to draw near to Him to experience all the benefits of their redemption, to declare their dependence on Him, to enjoy His appointed means of grace, to encourage one another, to celebrate their union with Jesus Christ and to be transformed, more and more, into His image.</p><p>3. In the corporate worship of the church the triune God meets with His people in accordance with the terms of the Covenant of Grace. In worship the church remembers God\'s covenant of grace and renews her commitment to her Lord. Worship involves intimate communion between God and His redeemed people. In worship God initiates a covenantal dialogue with His people in which He calls them to worship, declares to them His great acts of creation and redemption, assures them of the efficacy of His promises, and seals His promises to them by means of sacraments. In response to God\'s initiative, the people of God offer prayers of confession, petition, and thanksgiving, sing Psalms with grace in their hearts, receive God\'s word as it is both read and preached, make offerings to Him and seal their personal and corporate commitment to Him through the sacraments.</p><p>4. Because worship involves drawing near to the living and holy God, God\'s people should enter public worship prepared for communion with Him. In addition, pastors and elders should lead the congregation in public worship in a manner commensurate with the joy, dignity, solemnity and glory of such a holy occasion. All of God\'s people should enter His presence with both reverence and awe.</p><p>5. Jesus Christ is the sole mediator of the Covenant of Grace and the only mediator between God and man. Therefore, the worship of God\'s people is acceptable to God only as it is offered in Christ\'s name and through humble reliance on His High Priestly intercession and service.</p><p>6. Jesus Christ, as our Prophet, Priest and King, has revealed to His people how to worship Him in a pleasing manner. Therefore, \"the acceptable way of worshiping the true God is instituted by Himself and so limited by His own revealed will, that He may not be worshiped according to the imaginations and devices of men, or the suggestions of Satan, under any visible representation, or any other way not prescribed in the Holy Scriptures\" (WCF 21:1).</p><p>7. In His Word, God has specially appointed one day in seven, the Sabbath day, for His people to assemble for the purpose of public corporate worship. Since the resurrection of our Lord, the first day of the week, the Lord\'s Day, has been set aside as the Christian Sabbath, to be kept holy as the day for the church\'s worship and for rest from regular work.</p><p>8. Given the high calling and privilege of public worship, the people of God should prepare their hearts and come to worship with a joyous willingness, not absenting themselves through indifference or because of family activities or other Christian meetings. In normal circumstances, neither personal devotions nor family worship are to be regarded as proper substitutes for public worship. In addition to attending the scheduled services of public worship, the Lord\'s Day may be fruitfully observed through activities such as: personal Bible reading and study, meditation and prayer, discussion of the sermon, the enjoyment of physical rest, acts of mercy, spiritual fellowship, hospitality, instructing and catechizing the children and visiting the sick.</p><p><b>Chapter 2 - The Practice of Worship</b></p><p>1. The Scriptures do not prescribe a fixed order of worship, but so that all things may be done decently and in order (I Cor. 14:40), it is desirable that the exercises of worship be conducted in a biblical, thoughtful, dignified, and edifying manner. The assembled congregation meets in God\'s presence as His covenant people: They confess their sins, hear His promises of forgiveness and acceptance, and listen to the righteous requirements of His Word. The whole is a dialogue between God and His people. The order and content of the service should reflect this dialogue that occurs on the basis of the Covenant of Grace. The following order of service is suggested, although it may be varied:</p><p>Call to Worship, and Greeting<br/>Prayer of Adoration<br/>Psalm<br/><i>Baptism, when administered</i><br/>Old Testament Reading<br/>Psalm, or Prayer of Confession<br/>New Testament Reading<br/>Prayer of Intercession<br/>Scripture Text for Sermon<br/>Sermon<br/>Prayer<br/>Presentation of Tithes and Offerings<br/><i>Lord\'s Supper, when administered:<br/>Words of Institution<br/>Warning and Invitation<br/>Celebration of the Lord\'s Supper</i><br/>Psalm<br/>Benediction</p><p>2. The scriptural elements of ordinary public worship are prayer, the singing of Psalms, the reading, preaching, and hearing of the Word of God, the presentation of tithes and offerings, and the celebration of the sacraments. To these may be added the special ordinances of fasting, thanksgiving, taking of oaths and vows, and public covenanting. Each part of the service should be briefly explained at regular intervals in contemporary terms, so as to make its purpose clear to all present. Announcements should be made prior to or after the service and kept to a minimum so as not to intrude upon the worship of God.</p><p>3. The local session is responsible for the immediate oversight of public worship. Ordinarily the pastor takes the leadership role in planning and conducting the worship service. Ruling elders may call the congregation to worship and give the greeting, lead the congregation in prayer, introduce the Psalms to be sung, and read the Scripture. On occasion a ruling elder may preach the Word and pronounce the benediction, but he may not administer the sacraments except under extraordinary circumstances (DCG 3:I:C:4-6). On occasion a student under care may lead part of the service.</p>]]></item>
        <item>Blah Blah</item>
        <item>Suggested Forms</item>
        <item>Blah Blah</item>
    </string-array>
    
    
</resources>
